Guide to the Allen G. Kukovich Papers, 1977-2004 AIS.2004.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allen G. Kukovich Papers
1977-2004
1985-2004
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Kukovich, Allen G.
AIS.2004.21
26.56 Linear Feet (17 boxes)
The documents in this collection primarily reflect the political initiatives of Allen G. Kukovich collection, a member of the Pennsylvania state legislature in both the House of Representatives (1977-1996) and the Senate (1996-2004).
Biography
Allen Kukovich graduated from Duquesne Law School in 1973 after receiving a B.A. in Political Science from Kent State University. After a short legal career, the 30 year old Democrat was elected to the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania in 1977. From 1989 to 1992, he served as House Majority Policy Committee Chairman. After eighteen years in the House, Kukovich moved on to a seat in the Senate in 1996, where he served the 39th District continuously until 2004. He was named Pennsylvania Democratic State Chairman from June 2002 until March 2003.
Perhaps Kukovich's most recognized achievement was the Children's Health Care Partnership Act, known as CHIP, which provides free or subsidized health insurance to uninsured Pennsylvania children. His other major legislative priorities include environmental, health care, economic development, senior citizen, legislative reform, and consumer protection issues.
Much of the above information was taken from http://www.kukovich.org. Additional information about Kukovich's career can be found at this website.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection primarily documents the legislative initiatives of Allen G. Kukovich as a State Congressman from 1977-2004. The collection is largely comprised of bills and related legislative material for which Kukovich was a primary sponsor or co-sponsor. Also included are supporting materials such as correspondence, memos, reports, articles, speeches, newspaper clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, and photographs. Topical strengths include CHIP, health care issues, and death penalty and judicial reform issues. The collection also includes extensive reports, plans, and correspondence concerning the proposed Maglev transportation project in Pittsburgh.
The papers are organized into twelve series by topic: I. Career Biography, 1977-2004; II. Health Care, 1981-2004; III. Environment and Transportation, 1981-2004; IV. Consumer Protection, 1977-2000; V. Criminal and Crime Reform, 1983-2004; VI. Children's Issues, 1985-2003; VII. Political Reform, 1979-2003; VIII. Economic Development, 1983-2000; IX. Poverty, 1985-2003; X. Municipal Grant Profiles, 1989-2004; XI. Other Initiatives and Organizational Involvements, 1981-2004; XII. Audio Visual Materials. Within each series, file folders were arranged topically as well as based on legislative initiatives. To manage the size of the collection, only those bills for which Kukovich was a sponsor or co-sponsor were saved during processing.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Allen Kukovich and Karen Mochar, Kukovich's Chief of Staff, November 2004.
Previous Citation
Allen G. Kukovich Papers, 1977-2004, AIS.2004.21, Archives Services Center, University of Pittsburgh
Pennsylvania -- Politics and government; Westmoreland County (Pa.) -- Politics and government; Pennsylvania -- Economic policy; Environmental protection -- Pennsylvania; Environmental policy -- Pennsylvania; Consumer protection -- Law and legislation -- Pennsylvania; Transportation -- Law and legislation -- Pennsylvania; Medical care -- Law and legislation -- Pennsylvania; Legislators -- Pennsylvania; Politics; Social action; Environment; Pennsylvania -- Economic conditions; Kukovich, Allen G.; Pennsylvania. Children's Health Care Partnership Act; Pennsylvania. General Assembly
- Career Biography, 1977-2004; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I contains general information about Kukovich's career, including awards, endorsements, campaign materials, and compilations of his achievements that were collected for his campaign. Also included are general press releases, clippings, correspondence, and speeches from his career, though items in these categories that clearly focused on a specific topic covered in Series II.-XI. were placed within the later series.
  - Legislative Achievement Summary Sheets, 1986-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee Appointment Letters, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Honors Lists, 1979-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Award Letters and Certificates, 1982-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - Endorsements, 1984-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Awards Clippings, 1978-2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Progressive Caucus Correspondence and Memos, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Collected Clippings of Accomplishments, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10-16)
  - Talking Points, n.d (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters to Supporters, 1984-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Election Clippings, 1977-1978, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Campaign Materials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Governor's Race Questionnaire, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Election Clippings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Opponent Lenny Santimyer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Press Release and Campaign Plans, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Campaign Materials and Clippings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Campaign Materials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Election Clippings, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Opponent Eugene Porterfield, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Campaign Materials, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Election Clippings, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Announcement Tour Schedule and Speech, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Candidacy Announcement, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Campaign Materials, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Press Releases, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Election Clippings, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Candidacy Announcement, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Campaign Plan, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Budget Wish Lists, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Budget Overview, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Budget Wish Lists, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 42-44)
  - Capital Budget Project Plans, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Press Releases, 1981-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
  - Clippings, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12-28)
  - Clippings, 1995-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
  - Clippings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Political Cartoons, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clippings-Kukovich and Senior Citizens, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings-Kukovich and Jobs/Labor, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania Report Kukovich Articles, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Constituent Correspondence-Education, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Constituent Correspondence-Backend Referendums, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Constituent Correspondence, 1986-2004 (Box 3, Folder 18-24)
  - Speech Preparation Materials, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars Speech, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Housing News Conference Speech, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Community Action Committee of the Lehigh Valley Speech, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Graduation Speech, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Latrobe Memorial Day Speech, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Commission Transportation Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Budget Message, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Central Westmoreland Chamber of Commerce Prayer Breakfast Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Clarion County Democratic Spring Banquet Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Smart Growth Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Prescription Drug Plan for Seniors Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reasons to Support the Ergonomics Standard Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Family and Consumer Sciences Association Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Teamsters Labor Speech, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Remembering 911 Speech, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Nonprofit Advocacy Speech, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Clarion Young Democrats Equality Rally Speech, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Social Welfare Policies and Legislation Speech, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Memorial Day Speech, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Radio Scripts, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Television Appearances, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Quotes on Issue Stances Prepared for Media, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Editor, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photographs
    - Mondale Rally, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Teamster Conference, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Allen Recognition Day (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Grant Presentation, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - School Visit, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Alzheimer's Association Chairperson, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Family, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Health Care, 1981-2004; II.
  Series II contains Kukovich's plan for free and low-cost child health care termed CHIP (Children's Health Insurance Program), which has been widely recognized as Kukovich's most significant contribution to the State of Pennsylvania. For other legislation to protect children, see Series VI. Children's Issues. Of almost equally enduring influence as CHIP are PACE and PACENET, which together provide assistance for prescription drug coverage to senior citizens in low income brackets. PACE/PACENET are well documented here, as are other senior protection measures such as Managed Care, the Older Adult Protective Services Act, the Medicare Overcharge Measure Act (MOM), and Guardianship and Family Caregiver bills. Kukovich was also firm in his support of the disabled; his efforts toward improved disability rights are included in this series. Of additional interest in this series are continued correspondence with popular health agencies including Blue Cross, Caring Foundation, Alzheimer's Association, and others.
  - CHIP Act Bill Overview and Fiscal Note, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - CHIP Expansion Bills, 1995-2002 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - CHIP Support Statements, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - House Health and Welfare Committee Hearing Testimonies, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Public Hearing Testimonies, 1991, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 37-40)
  - Eligibility and Enrollment Information, 1992-2004 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Instructions for Insurer Applicant, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Administrative Responses to Questions about CHIP, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1989-2003 (Box 4, Folder 44-48)
  - Memos, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Press Releases, 1993-2001 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - PowerPoint Presentation, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Speech, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Essay, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Speech Schedules, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Public Service Announcement, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Special Health Care Newsletter to Kukovich Supporters, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Articles written by Kukovich, 1998, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Clippings, 1989-2002 (Box 4, Folder 58-63)
  - Published Articles, 1993, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Pamphlets, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Fliers, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Physician Hospital and Dental Directories, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Blue Cross and Caring Foundation Newsletters, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Annual Report, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Advisory Council Meeting Report, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Tenth Anniversary Luncheon, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - CHIP Photos, c.2000 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Notes, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - PACE- Tobacco Settlement Information, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PACE- Senate Hearings, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - PACE- Expansion Senate Hearings, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - PACE- Expansion Senate Round Table Discussion, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - PACE- Advisory Committee Report, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PACE- Heinz Plan to Overcome Prescription Drug Expenses, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PACE- Governor Rendell's Plan to Expand, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - PACE- Bill Analyses and Reports, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PACE- Bill Analysis, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - PACE- Bill Summaries Talking Points and Fiscal Notes, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - PACE- Correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - PACE- Press Releases, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - PACE- Memos, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - PACE- Clippings, 2001-2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - HB 1886 Working File, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - HB 1886 Meeting of, January 14, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - HB 1886 Amendments, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Managed Care- Bills, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Managed Care- Package, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Managed Care- Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Managed Care- Horror Stories, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Managed Care- Memos, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Managed Care- Press Releases and Clippings, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Managed Care- Health Insurance Consumer Bill of Rights, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Managed Care- Testimonies, 1996, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Managed Care- Report, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Managed Care- Accountability Coalition Papers, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Physician Referral Bill, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Older Adult Protective Services Act and Fiscal Note, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Protective Services Act Testimonies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Protective Services Act Correspondence and Memos, 1985-2000 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
  - Protective Services Act Clippings, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Indigent Health Care Bill, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Health Care Cost Containment, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - MOM- Act Bills and Fact Sheets, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - MOM- House Hearing, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2-5)
  - MOM- Testimony from Medical Organizations, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MOM- Senate Hearing, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - MOM- Kukovich's Presentation and Press Conferences, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - MOM- Endorsements, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - MOM- Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MOM- Press Releases and Clippings, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Campaign for Affordable Health Care, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Action Alliance of Seniors Memos, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Health Care Complaint Statistics, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Guardianship Bills and Fiscal Notes, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Report of the General Assembly Subcommittee on Guardianships, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Guardianship Fact Sheets, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Pennsylvania Bankers Association Guardianship Testimony, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Department of Aging Guardianship Report, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Associated Press Guardianship Report, c. 1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Pennsylvania Developmental Disabilities Council Guardianship Report, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Westmoreland County Area Agency on Aging Guardianship Report, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Guardianship Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
  - Guardianship Memos and Press Releases, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Guardianship Clippings and Articles, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Guardianship Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - SB 5 vs. HB 1000, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - SB 5 Fact Sheets and Clippings, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Amendment to HB 221 Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Testimony of United Mental Health Inc., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Pennsylvania Protection and Advocacy Inc. Plan for the Mentally Ill, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Alliance for the Mentally Ill Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Mental Health Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Mental Health Clippings and Notes, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Health Care Personnel Shortage House Hearings, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Family Caregiver Support Act, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family Caregiver Regulations, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Family Caregiver Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Family Caregiver Reports, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania Department of Aging Conference Recommendations, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Alzheimer's Association Pre-HB 698 Correspondence and Reports (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Alzheimer's Association Correspondence and Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Alzheimer's Association Public Policy Forum Agenda and Guide to Policy Priorities, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Family Caregiver Press Releases Clippings and Articles, 1989-2002 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania Department of Aging Pamphlets on Family Caregiving, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Family Caregiver Cost Sharing Guideline, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Attendant Care Program Act, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Reports on Attendant Care, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Attendant Care Correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Attendant Care Press Release and Clipping, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Privacy Act, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Hospice Act, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Nursing Licensure Bill, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Department of Public Welfare Presentations-Community Resource Centers, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Department of Public Welfare PowerPoint Presentation-Community Resource Centers, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Community Resource Centers QA's, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Community Resource Center Advocate Correspondence, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Listing of Community Resource Centers, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Disability Budget Coalition Meeting Minutes and Memos, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Disability Budget Coalition Agenda and Reports, 1994-2001 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Pennsylvania's Community Services Program for Persons with Physical Disabilities Report, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Handicapped Parking Fine Increase Legislation, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - People First Resolution, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Health and Welfare Council of Westmoreland County Speech, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Pennsylvania Community Providers Association Speech, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Long Term Care Forum, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Cardiovascular Care Conference Speech, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Pennsylvania Community Providers Speech, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - National Respite Care Speech, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Northern Area Personal Care Home Administrator's Association Speech, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Staunton Farm Foundation Speech, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Kukovich's Remarks on the Welfare Reform Bill, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - University of Pittsburgh Health Care Reform Forum, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Westmoreland County Health Care Roundtable Discussion, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Environment and Transportation, 1981-2004; III.
  Series III contains materials related to environmental and transportation issues. Beginning in the late 1990s, Kukovich was actively involved in the fight to have Pittsburgh selected from among several candidates to receive funding for a high speed magnetic rail system by Maglev Corporation. This series includes studies and reports that cover this planning process. The remainder of the series focuses primarily on environmental issues supported by the Congressman, including the Clean Air Act and renewable energy. Of interest is Kukovich's stance on emissions testing because it placed two issues of importance to him in conflict: though he supported the environmental aspects of the bill, he ultimately opposed it because of the burden it placed on the consumer.
  - High Speed Intercity Rail Passenger Commission Act, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Maglev- Defined Need Report, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Maglev- Proposal Plan and Feasibility Study II, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Maglev- Discussions, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Maglev- Meeting Report and Business Plan Overview, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Maglev- FRA Review Meeting, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Maglev- Deployment Program, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Maglev- Legislative Update, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Maglev- Planning Meetings, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Maglev- Public Meeting Guide, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Maglev- Transit Visions Policy Conference Materials, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Maglev- Reports and Q As, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Maglev- Media Conference, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Maglev- Correspondence, 1993-2003 (Box 8, Folder 16-20)
  - Maglev- Articles, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Maglev- Clippings and Press Releases, 1991-2002 (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
  - Maglev- Pamphlets, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Maglev- CargoLifter Inc. Information, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Emissions- Program Final Report and Overview, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Emissions- Fact Sheets, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Emissions- Testimony and Floor Remarks, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Emissions- Testing Press Releases, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Emissions- Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Emissions- Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Clean Air Bill, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Federal Clean Air Act Compliance Letter, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Kukovich's U.S. Congressional Testimony on Clean Air Act, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Pennsylvania Clean Air Act Hearing Testimonies, 1981, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Clean Air Act Correspondence, 1981-1999 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Clean Air Act Press Release, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Clean Air Act Clippings, 1990-1997 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - PennCONSERVE, 2001-2004 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Energy Policy, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Alternative Energy, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Thornburgh and Kukovich Energy Ads, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Renewable Energy Conference Speech, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Natural Gas Bills Press Conferences Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - PENNVEST Reports, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - PENNVEST Correspondence and Press Releases, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - PENNVEST Press Packet, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - House Research of Municipal Sewer Water and Solid Waste Authorities, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Water and Sewer Improvement Bond Issue Bill, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Consumer Protection, 1977-2000; IV.
  Series IV spans many different consumer issues, from plain language in legal documentation to tort reform, though it lacks depth on any given topic.
  - Kukovich's Consumer Protection Legislative History, c. 1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Consumer Omnibus Bill Explanations and Testimony, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Consumer Omnibus Clippings and Correspondence, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Plain Language- Bills, 1981-1993 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Plain Language- Testimony, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Plain Language- Correspondence, 1983-1994 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Plain Language- Press Releases, 1985, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Plain Language- Articles and Clippings, 1981-1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Product Liability- Fact Sheets, 1980 and undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Product Liability- Pennsylvania Product Liability Act Commentary, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
  - Product Liability- Reform Senate Hearing Testimony, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Product Liability- Report of the National Science Foundation, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Product Liability- Pennsylvania Civil Justice Coalition Report-Liability Insurance, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Product Liability- Review of Bill by AFL-CIO, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Product Liability- Report on Tort Law, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Product Liability- Correspondence with Pennsylvania Trial Lawyers Association, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Product Liability- General Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Product Liability- Clippings, 1980-1999 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Product Liability- Kukovich's Comments and Notes (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - House Hearing on Utilities Reform, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 31)